Subrip by dandee
Well ?
Sir , I just want to come back and finish my studies .
Being a doctor and serving society has always been my main goal in life .
I don 't want my future destroyed because of one mistake .
So , do you admit it ?
Admit what ?
What you 've done .
Well , I don 't know the details of my case
but I guess the reason I can 't return is because I was politically active .
But sir , everyone was politically active during the revolution .
I was young . Naive .
I mean , I didn 't even understand the difference between left and right .
I was just passionate like everyone else that age .
I was concerned about the country . I wanted change .
I 'm sure you understand .
If I ended up in one of those radical left groups ...
It was only because I didn 't know any better ...
Every mistake has consequences .
I let you in so you could hear this directly from my lips
and stop wasting your time by coming here every day .
Let me tell you this frankly .
You cannot continue your studies .
Based on your history , there is not even the slightest possibility
that you can ever return to the university .
I suggest you find a new goal in life .
- Hello , Mrs. Fakur . - Hello , dear .
Sorry , I 'm late . I hope Dorsa wasn 't any trouble ?
No trouble at all . We had fun .
Dorsa ! Mum !
- What happened ? - Mummy .
Oh , darling
it 's okay .
It 's okay . I understand . That 's the climate right now .
Don 't let it change you .
To my daughter .
Congratulations on beginning medical school .
I 'm proud of you . Your loving mother .
Hello ? Anyone home ?
Dad , dad , dad , dad !
Hello , little one .
Where 's mum ?
She 's in the bedroom .
She 's grumpy .
Hello ...
What are you doing ?
Those are my course books .
Give them away to someone who wants them . Or chuck them .
Go and play Dorsa .
What happened ?
Maybe things will get better after the war .
There 's no guarantee .
And this war seems to be never ending .
Well , you 've tried your best .
It 's out of your hands now .
Who knows ? It 's probably for the best .
Dorsa ! Run !
Where are you going ?
There is no time , we have to go downstairs !
We can 't leave Kimia behind .
Come on .
Hello . Hello .
Thank you , Doctor .
- Sorry for the trouble . - Not at all .
Thank God , sounds like they 've put more defenses around Tehran .
I heard a rumor that Iraq is launching missiles now ...
Leave her alone .
Dorsa , come here , sweetheart .
Who 's this new boy ?
Mr. Ebrahimi 's nephew . Apparently he lost his parents in the Abadan .
Dad ?
What happened , sweetheart ?
Did you have a bad dream ?
It 's okay .
No , dear , those things don 't exist .
Next time you 're scared , remember that you 're not on your own .
I gave you Kimia to keep you company .
Good morning .
No toys at the breakfast table please .
The tape on the windows is coming off .
What if the windows shatter in a blast ...
I 'll re-tape them .
Did you have a nightmare last night ?
She said she heard someone walking in the house .
You 're a bad sleeper just like your mother .
Did you sleep okay last night ?
Me ?
Why do you think I 'm sleepwalking again ?
You would have noticed .
I was out cold .
Just because I did it once or twice
like six months ago , doesn 't mean it 's a constant thing .
Plus this is not the first time Dorsa has had a nightmare and imagined things .
I 'm just saying you 're only a bad sleeper when you 're stressed .
What 's that ?
It 's my ...
Annual draft notice .
Why didn 't you mention it sooner ?
You 've had other things on your mind .
I 'm going to the Ministry of Health later today to see where I 'm stationed .
Might get somewhere safe like last year ...
If we 're lucky ...
Hey , Doctor .
- A minute please ... - Hello .
- Hello ... How is your family ? - Good , thank you .
How many times do I have to ask for the garage door to be closed properly ?
- Please remind your wife ... - What do you mean ?
Let me show you .
The bolt has rusted .
- It takes force to put it in place ... - How do you know it was my wife ?
It 's not you or me .
I know Mr. Fakur closes it properly .
And none of the women in the building drive , apart from your wife .
Right . We 'll remember to close the door properly .
Have a good day .
Hello .
They 're sending me to Elam .
That 's in the middle of the fighting .
I tried for a safer post but it didn 't work out .
I think you and Dorsa should go to my parents .
Why ?
The rumors about Iraq using missiles are probably true .
It 's safer up North . People are already leaving the city .
We 're fine here .
You don 't get a warning with missiles .
I 'm not going to be a burden to your parents .
You 're not a burden .
Last time we went there your sisters kept saying
" Tehran gets bombed and we get the shrapnel . "
We 'll be fine in our own home .
I 'm worried about Dorsa .
What ? Am I not capable of looking after my own child now ?
That 's not what I 'm saying .
All I 'm saying is I won 't be around .
At my parents ' , you can at least have that support .
Ah , because you 've been so supportive until now ...
That 's unfair .
No , unfair is you swanking off to play doctors and treating me like ...
I 'm incompetent .
Play doctors ?
Being shipped off to war is not a game .
Are you showing off ? Do you want a medal ?
I 'm not going out of choice . I 'd lose my right to practice ...
If you don 't have the right to practice , it 's a catastrophe
but if I don 't it 's for the best .
Are you mad that I 'm practicing ?
No , I 'm not mad about that ...
Dorsa , how many times have I told you to put your toys away after playing ?
Is it my fault you can 't finish your studies ?
Didn 't you waste your time on politics at university ?
You sound exactly like them .
Am I wrong ?
Have you forgotten that you kept calling me spineless for sticking to my studies ?
Like you never tried to stop me studying .
When did I ever do that ?
When the universities reopened after the Cultural Revolution
who was it that told me studying could wait , stay home and raise the child ?
Do you have a problem looking after your child ?
Are you calling me a bad mother ?
No . I 'm saying don 't blame your shortcomings on me and our child .
Tell me , why do you want to go back now , all of a sudden ?
I didn 't leave out of choice . The Cultural Revolution happened .
That was four , five years ago . The universities reopened after a year .
So ?
You only want to go back now because your mother died ...
Becoming a doctor has always been my dream !
No , Shideh , it 's your mother 's dream .
Dead people can 't dream .
I 'll be scared without you here .
I 'll be back before you know it !
Mum is going to take you to granny 's .
Here 's this month 's rent and what we owed from last month .
Give it to Ebrahimi when it 's due to shut him up .
Mum ...
Yes ?
My bed is wet .
Get up .
You still have to wet yourself at this age !
Aren 't you going to school next year ?
Go to the bathroom , take your clothes off .
Didn 't I say go to the bathroom ?
I 'm scared to go alone ...
Your toast .
Mummy ?
Now that dad is not here ... Can I sleep next to you at night ?
Aren 't you a big girl ?
Big girls don 't wet the bed either .
Why do you have trouble sleeping ?
Well ? Tell me . What are you scared of ?
Hey ?
Djinn ...
Djinn aren 't real ...
They are . We just can 't see them .
- Who told you that ? - Mehdi .
Who 's Mehdi ?
Sogand and Ali 's cousin .
He gave me a ball of magical cat fur to protect myself from them .
But I lost it .
Drink properly .
Djinn are just a fairytale made up to scare little children .
Mehdi said Djinn are real . They 're evil and want to hurt us ...
Mehdi is talking nonsense .
- Hello , Mrs. Ebrahimi . - Hello ...
- I hope it 's not a bad time . - Not at all . Please come in .
No , thanks . I just have a small request ...
- Your relative ... - Mehdi ?
He has been telling scary stories to my daughter , Dorsa .
I know he 's just a child , it 's nothing spiteful
but Dorsa is having real trouble sleeping at night .
Please ask him not to tell Dorsa those kind of stories ...
Your daughter has made a mistake .
Mehdi is mute .
He hasn 't said a word since he lost his parents .
They both got killed .
Ebrahimi took him to so many different doctors .
But no result .
- She said Mehdi told her ... - Has she said what stories ?
- Djinn and stuff ... - Oh , God , have mercy !
Djinn aren 't Mrs. Ebrahimi ...
They are very real . It 's even in the Quran .
My husband gets angry when I say this , but the boy is creepy ...
- You 're back early . - Mrs. Ebrahimi sent me back upstairs .
Didn 't she say why ?
She took Sogand and Ali home and told me to go home too .
What about Mehdi ?
Mehdi 's allowed to stay .
But we can 't play with him anymore .
You know , the stories you mentioned this morning ...
Are you sure it was Mehdi that told them to you and not the Ebrahimi kids ?
Well , Sogand and Ali also tell me stories .
Why be careful ?
Because they 're coming .
Did he say that in front of the Ebrahimi kids ?
No , he whispered it in my ear .
Oh my , we 've talked so much . Your tea is getting cold .
You are right . Sorry .
Beep , beep , beep , beep .
What lovely tea you 've made .
I didn 't know that you could make such tasty tea .
Thank you .
- Have some bread too . - Yes , yes , I will .
Hello ?
- Shideh ? - Hello .
- Can you hear me ? - The line isn 't great but it 's okay .
- How are you ? - We 're fine . How is it over there ?
Not great .
Either working in the hospital or taking shelter .
You still don 't want to go to my parents ?
Don 't worry about us .
The foreign radios are saying Iraq claims they 'll level Tehran with missiles soon .
Nothing has been reported here .
Please take Dorsa out of the city .
I 'm not abandoning my home based on a rumor .
- Not even for Dorsa ? - Dorsa is better off in her own home .
I have to go . Think about what I said .
I miss you .
- Bye . - I miss you too ...
400 miles from the battlefield ...
Tehran will become the new front line for the ongoing Iran-Iraq war .
Iraq has started launching missiles , reaching out ...
- Where did you go , ma 'am ? Your tea is getting cold . - Hold on .
- Many Iranians have already left the capital ... - What about our tea party ?
- Playtime is over - It 's not . It 's not . It 's not .
Enough ! When I say playtime 's over , I mean it !
If you don 't listen to me
next time I 'll take Kimia away so you can 't play with her .
- Understand ? - Did it hurt ?
It 's okay . I 'm here . I 'll look after you .
Dorsa !
Come here please .
Are you still mad at me ?
We need to go downstairs right now !
Dorsa !
Somebody ...
Help me !
Please !
Dorsa ? Sweetheart ?
Dorsa ?
Please answer me ...
Oh , my sweetheart ...
- I saw them . They 're real . They were scary . - Saw who ?
- I saw them ... - What are you talking about ? Shideh .
Please ... My dad ... My dad is dying .
- Please help . - Mum ! Don 't leave me !
Please ! Help my father ! Save my dad . You 're a doctor . You can .
- But I 'm not a doctor ... - Mum ! Don 't go !
- I 'll look after Dorsa . Go . - No , Mum ! No !
Come here . He 's here . Hurry !
- Mr. Bijari ? - Father !
Let 's take him out of here .
We can 't be here . This missile might still explode !
Go and call an ambulance ! If I don 't do CPR now , he 'll die .
Dad ... My poor dad ... Come on .
Come on .
Come .
Paramedics . It 's safe , you can come up .
If I was a real doctor , he might still be alive .
Why do you say this ?
You did everything you could .
- What 's going on ? - Nothing , darling . Go back to sleep .
She 's not here !
Kimia ... Kimia is not here .
- Where was it before ? - On the bed ...
- They took her . - Nobody took it .
It 's probably around here somewhere ...
Are you okay ?
You 're so hot !
Oh , my baby ... My sweet , baby girl ...
They came and saw she was alone and took her .
Don 't worry . You should rest for now .
Take your shoes off .
Keep warm and rest until your fever breaks .
I promise to find her . Okay ?
Mum , I had a bad dream .
Don 't be afraid .
Dorsa ?
What are you doing ?
Going to get Kimia !
I think she 's upstairs ... They 've taken her upstairs ... I want to go , find her ...
Let 's go back to bed .
- You need to eat something . - I can 't .
You have to eat if you want to get better .
Do you know what I 'm going to do after breakfast ?
I 'll put a video on for you .
You can lie in front of the TV all day and watch whatever you want .
But only if you eat breakfast .
- Dorsa ? - Yes ?
- Have you seen my workout tape ? - No .
It was here but I can 't find it now .
- I never touch the tapes . - I didn 't say you did .
Who is it ?
Glazier .
Just a second ...
- Hello . - Hello .
Business must be good at the moment with all the attacks .
Problem is , the missus insists that it 's too dangerous to stay .
- Wants us to move out of town ... - Mum .
I had my breakfast . So , put the video on for me please .
- You said you would . - Let 's go outside and let the man work .
How many times have I told you not to say we have a VCR , in front of a stranger ?
Do you want the authorities to find out and take it away ?
But I 'm bored ... I want Kimia .
I told you I 'll find Kimia .
- Hello , Shideh ... - Hello ...
This is for you .
For what ?
For your help yesterday .
I 'm also here to say goodbye .
Goodbye ?
- I 'm going back to Kurdistan for a while . - But it 's so dangerous over there .
My father always wanted to be buried in his hometown .
Dorsa , my dear .
Remember , yesterday after the missile hit , you said you saw something or someone ?
Pargol ?
- You said they were scary . You were crying . - Pargol ? Go inside .
Dorsa is a child . She imagines things when she 's scared ...
You probably think I 'm going crazy ...
But my father was fine yesterday after the missile hit .
He was talking to me . I swear .
I left the room to get him a glass of water and then I heard him scream .
I ran back and saw ...
He looked so terrified .
His eyes were fixed on something behind me I couldn 't see .
Something terrifying ...
Like ...
I understand how hard it is to deal with the death of someone so close .
You know I lost my mother six months ago .
But it was the shock of the missile that gave your father a heart attack .
- Is she still the same ? - Yeah .
The fever still won 't break .
Maybe you should take her to a doctor ...
I mean , like a pediatrician .
I can 't stand any more of this , Ebrahimi .
You have to close up shop and take us out of town .
If our tenants would only pay what they owe
then I could close up shop . Mrs. Ebrahimi is right .
I 've told Fakur that we have to leave everything and go to our son 's in Paris .
We just renewed our visas , so I see no reason to sit through this .
I missed you .
I 'm here for Dorsa .
I always knew you were useless .
- This can 't be real . - Why not ?
Where did you go , ma 'am ?
Your tea is getting cold ... No , playtime is not over !
It was on the bed .
Nothing .
Nothing here either .
- Shideh , could you have dreamt it ? - It was too real .
What 's my workout video doing in the bin ?
I 'm talking to you .
Dorsa ?
Dorsa ... What are you doing ?
Where is she ?
I want her back ! Give her back !
- What are you doing here ? - I 'm looking for Kimia .
- Here you go . - Thank you very much .
Finally some peace .
Ebrahimi went out and took the children with him .
So , how is little Dorsa ?
- She 's a little under the weather . - Oh , God .
Nothing serious , I hope ? No , just a cold I think .
Have you heard any strange noises around the building recently ?
If this is about Dorsa 's screams earlier in the stairway
I apologize . She has been a bit restless because of her fever .
Mehdi has been very restless too but he doesn 't seem to be ill .
I knew he 'd bring trouble with him .
Please don 't say such things , Mrs. Ebrahimi .
I don 't think you get it .
That thing didn 't crash here by accident .
I think it brought something with it ...
Like what ?
Djinn .
Djinn belong to fairy tales .
This is not A Thousand and One Nights .
You 're wrong .
They travel on the wind from place to place until they find someone to possess .
Why are you telling me this ?
Why was Dorsa outside Bijari 's apartment , banging on the door ?
I told you she 's delirious because of her high fever .
She was looking for someone .
Her favorite doll is missing . She thinks it has somehow gone to the fourth floor .
I think I should go now ...
You know , if they take a personal belonging ...
Something that you treasure ...
Then there 's no escape from them .
You 'll be marked and they 'll always know how to find you .
Sorry , I 'm late . Mrs. Ebrahimi accosted me .
- What time is your flight ? - Early morning .
You must be excited to see your son .
The missile attacks have actually been a good excuse .
He has missed us lots too . Even wanted to come back .
I had to remind him that they 'd have him conscripted and sent
conscripted the front line as soon as he landed !
What are you looking for ?
I remember you had this book , The People of the Air , by Saedi .
Yes , we have . Second shelf . The contemporaries .
Do you know what it 's about ?
Djinn .
It 's about superstitious belief in Djinn , down South ...
And how they travel on the wind .
It 's an anthropological book , not a book to find answers in .
What answers ?
I 'm just saying
people can convince themselves anything 's real if they want to .
The winds refer to mysterious , ethereal and magical forces
which can be anywhere ...
Where there is fear and anxiety , the winds blow .
I 'm glad I got hold of you .
I thought you 'd have left the city like everyone else .
I sent the family away .
I 'll join them during the weekend .
- Have you heard from anyone recently ? - Not really .
I 've been to the university a few times and seen a few old faces .
Can you believe there are still people from our time who haven 't finished ?
They 're obviously not doctor material ...
- Did your own problem get sorted ? - No .
Take a deep breath , sweetheart .
I give her paracetamol three times a day .
Also started with antibiotics when I saw the fever wasn 't breaking .
There 's no sign of internal infection .
So , why isn 't her fever breaking ?
Shideh , can I borrow you for a second ?
Sit down , sweetheart .
Is everything okay at home ?
Yes , why ?
Everyone 's under a lot of strain right now .
Dorsa is no exception . It could be stress related .
Everything 's fine .
How about you ? Are you okay ?
Yes .
I 'm fine .
What are you doing here on your own ?
Do you need a lift ?
Get in .
Where is her doll ?
Where have you been , you little sod ?
Hi , thanks for dropping him off .
- I saw him down the road ... - Do you want us to leave you behind ?
- Is that what you want ? - Leave him alone . It 's okay ...
How 's little Dorsa ?
The same . Are you leaving too ?
What else can we do ? Take care of yourself . Goodbye .
Sorry ...
Have a safe trip .
Please make sure you close the door properly now that we are away .
- What are you doing ? - We are leaving too .
We can 't . What about Kimia ?
Okay . Try to remember the last time you saw it .
It 's not there now . So , where else could it be ?
- I don 't know - It didn 't walk off on its own .
- Someone took her . - Who ? Who took it ?
There 's nobody here except for us . Do you understand ?
- Why are you shouting at me ? - Because I 'm tired of this silly game .
If nobody took her , where is she ?
I didn 't move her .
Just like you didn 't move my workout video , I suppose ?
I said I didn 't touch your workout video !
How did it end up in the bin then ?
The doll is around here somewhere .
It hasn 't left the house and nobody has taken it .
If I didn 't move her and nobody took her , then where is she ?
I suppose I took her then , right ?
Please ... We can 't leave Kimia behind ...
I 'll be scared without her .
And I 'll stay sick forever .
Don 't you want me to get better ?
If you love me , please help me find her ...
Okay ... But we 'll leave as soon as we find it .
You can sleep next to me tonight , if you want .
Maybe it 's over .
Let 's just stay a bit longer .
What 's wrong ?
Hi ... Do you know where she is ?
On top of where ? The bookcase ?
Who are you talking to ?
That lady . She was standing right there .
What 's this look ? Are we in Swiss now ?
Here , cover yourself with this . I 'll go and speak to the Haji .
What were you thinking ? You know your crime is punishable with lashes .
So , pray that he shows mercy .
Stand up .
Look , I 'm letting you off this time with a warning
only because Mrs. Hashemi has vouched for you .
Go and thank God that she did .
Because this behavior is absolutely intolerable .
A woman should be scared of exposing herself more than anything else .
So , be ashamed .
These are not the old times . We have values now .
Our men are becoming martyrs to protect these values ...
What are you doing ?
Nothing ...
- Looking for Kimia ... - Up there ?
I thought maybe she was up there .
I told you I 'd find it .
You really need to rest , especially with your fever .
You hardly had any sleep last night .
Promise me that you 'll find her .
I promise .
My dear ...
Hello ?
- Hello ? Shideh ? - Hello ? Hello ?
- Why are you still there ? - Hi .
Please . Can you not be stubborn about this under the circumstances ?
I 'm not being stubborn .
- Everyone 's fleeing Tehran . - But ...
- But what ? - Something has gone missing . I have to find it first .
- What ? - You wouldn 't understand , you haven 't been here .
I 'm just hearing excuses . I think its best I get my parents to contact you ...
No
and officially invite you .
- Listen to me ... - I know you well enough . You 're just a ...
Hello ? You 're cutting out ... Hello ?
Who is it ?
Dorsa ! Dorsa , open the door !
Where were you ?
Did you see anyone ?
Who ?
I don 't know ... Like a lady ?
- Who is she ? - I don 't know .
She comes when you 're not around .
What does she do ?
She plays with me . She 's nice .
What does she want ?
She says ...
You can 't look after me but she can .
That 's nonsense .
She says she knows where Kimia is . She can help me find her ...
This is all in your head . She 's not real .
But you said you saw her too .
To the last person , to the last home
and to the last drop of blood
we are standing in exaltation at the word , God .
- Mum , can I go back to bed ? - No .
You 've to stay where I can see you .
On the sofa ?
Didn 't we agree not to come in here anymore ? The room is off limits .
- If I can 't be there , then why are you ? - Because I 'm looking for your doll .
The lady was right .
What did you say ? I 'm sick of this nonsense !
I don 't want to hear about this lady anymore , whether she 's real or not !
Understand ?
I 'll run off with her then !
Stop it !
Stop !
Please ... Have me instead ...
Please ...
Dorsa ?
I woke up and you weren 't here .
- I heard noises . - What noises ?
Hello ?
Shideh , have you found what you were looking for yet ?
Hello , Iraj .
You might find this hard to believe , but ...
But I really think there is something haunting us .
They 've taken Dorsa 's doll and ... I have to find it ...
If I don 't , they 'll never leave Dorsa alone ...
But you can 't protect Dorsa .
You 're useless ! You 're nothing but a disappointment !
Even your daughter hates you !
- Shut up ! - No , you shut up , whore !
You brought this on yourself !
Go away !
What is that ?
Your loving mother ...
Why did you do that ?
You killed her ! You killed her !
- I didn 't do it . - Liar !
They did it . The ones you talk about .
That 's your drawer ! You hide your things in it !
That 's why they put it in here . They want you to think that I did it .
But you said they 're not real .
Okay . The important thing is we found her .
But she 's dead !
- I 'll fix her . - How ?
Lie on the bed and close your eyes .
It 'll be fixed when you open them .
It 's okay , I 'm a doctor .
Dorsa .
Look !
Your fever has gone .
You know I love you , right ?
Right ?
We 'll be downstairs until the danger is over
and then we 'll leave and go to granny 's .
I don 't want to stay here anymore .
Wear your coat .
It 's not here . Maybe it 's in your room .
Let 's go . I 'm right behind you .
I 'm right here !
Wait for me .
Why aren 't you coming ?
Did you hear something ?
Mum ! Mum ! Mum !
Please , Mum ...
Help me , Mum !
Please !
It sounds like you .
- Dorsa ! - Don 't go !
Dorsa !
Dorsa , I 'm coming !
Dorsa ! Mummy 's coming !
I 'm coming ! I 'm coming !
- Mummy ! - Leave her alone !
Dorsa !
Mummy !
- Mummy ! - Dorsa ?
- Dorsa ? - Mummy !
- I 'm here , sweetheart . - Mummy !
- Mummy ... It has got me ! - I 've got you !
- Dorsa ? - Don 't come close .
Why did you leave me again ?
I made a mistake .
- What ? - Whom are you talking to ?
The lady ... She says you took Kimia !
- Me ? - She says you were hiding it !
- No . She 's lying . - You 're lying . You took it .
- Don 't lie . - Yes . Maybe .
I 'm not sure . I really don 't know ...
But I know I love you very much . I 'm telling you the truth .
If I 've upset you in any way , I 'm sorry .
I didn 't mean to . Please forgive me .
I know you 're scared . I am too . Come over here .
Let 's leave , then we won 't be afraid ... Come here , sweetheart .
Mum !
Mum , please help me !
Dorsa !
- Mum ! - Dorsa !
Mum , please help me ...
Don 't leave me ...
Don 't leave me !
Oh , my God !
Are you okay , my dear ?
Go ! I 'll come too . Hurry up .
No . Don 't come to me . Don 't step on the ground .
Go up .
Run ...
Run !
Kimia !
Hurry up ...
Get in .
Shit !
Mum ... What is wrong ?
Mum ...
- Mum ? - Come to the front .